亲爱的
Honey?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
Yeah. Yeah.
还有点消化不良
I'm just fighting off a stomach bug.
会好的
I'll be fine.
他睡得好么?
Did he sleep okay?
很好, 只要我抱着他就行
Great,as long as i s holding him.
盼着宝宝的哭闹期早点结束
I can't wait for colic to be over.
来咯, mikey, 洗澡澡
There you go,mikey.Bath time's coming.
他昨天抬起头了
He lifted his head yesterday.
今天休息吧
Take the day off.
你都生病了, 再说,多久没有好好看看我俩了
I mean,you're sick anyway,and you hardly ever see him.Or me.
不行啊
I can'T.
要和crandall厨具公司开会, 应该能成交
I got a meeting with crandall's kitchens.I think that deal's gonna close.
车贷的钱又催过了
They called about the car payment again.
迟交两个月了
It's two months late.
会没事的, 亲爱的
We're gonna be fine,honey.
好好洗澡, 小家伙
Enjoy your bath,little man.
唔, 亲爱的...
You know,honey...
亲爱的, 我今天不去了
honey,I'm not gonna go in.
有点不舒服
I'm coming down with something.
亲爱的?
Honey?
Kara.
Kara
Kara?Kara!
Kara? Kara!
Mikey!Mikey! Mikey.
Mikey! Mikey! Mikey
Kara!Mikey!
Kara! Mikey!
在浴缸里发生意外,不知持续多久
called in for some emergency in bathtub,Don't know how long.
当场无反应
Non-responsive at the scene.
现在呼吸了
Obviously breathing now.
继续辅助呼吸, 立即作胸透
Continue the blow-by.Stat portable chest.
高加索人, 女性, 32岁
Caucasian,female,32.
- 我在哪里?,- 在浴室里强直阵挛
Where am I?--Tonic-clonic seizure in the bathroom.
出什么事了? Brent, 我在哪儿?
What happened?Brent,where am I?
快, 1, 2, 3
Come on,one,two,three.
数到3-- 1, 2, 3
On three--one,two,three.
你在医院里. 亲爱的, 在医院了
You're in the hospital.honey,you're in hospital.
Mikey 也在这里, 医生说他会没事
Mikey's here,and the doctors say he's gonna be okay.
希望如此,要经过新生儿重症室 (nicu) 观察
Hopefully.He needs to be checked out by the nicu.
怎么了?
what happened?
你昏过去了
You passed out.
Mikey 溺水
Mikey fell.
- 你妻子以前有突然抽搐吗?,- 没有
Has your wife had a seizure before?--No.
我要看看他!
I want to see him!
他就在这儿. 没事的, 亲爱的,他就在这儿
He's right here.He's okay,honey.He's right here.
今晚...一口气看 "拉拉至上"
Tonight...l word marathon.
你看  "拉拉至上" ?
You watch the l word?
静音地
On mute.
我还是不看了
I'll pass.
和 cuddy 约了晚饭
Dinner with cuddy.
还在拍马屁让她出钱,给化疗的孩子一个乐园?
Still sucking up so she'll fund your play space for the chemo kids?
这些小孩还是省省力气吧, 哭哭算了
They really ought to save their energy for other things.Like crying.
她求我的
She's the suck-up.
她邀请你的?
She asked you?
聪明如她, 自然知道, 三杯酒下肚
She's smart.She knows if she buys me enough alcohol,
我就不设防了
my defenses just might be weakened.
想不通, 除非她电池用完了,(电动自慰器)
Doesn't make sense.Unless she ran out of batteries.
嘿... 我俩都是孤家寡人
Hey...I'm recently single.She's single.
你太善良了, 她不会喜欢
You're too nice for her to like you.
她不够困苦, 你也不会喜欢
She's not needy enough for you to like her.
她明确的很, 不会接受长得像小吉米的,(美国乡村乐名歌手)
She's got an agenda,just not one that includes an appearance by little jimmy.
我来让小鸭子们投票
I'll poll my peeps.
多少人认为是cuddy邀请--,只有一只在
How many of you think that cuddy asked--or rather,"peep."
Chase 在急救室碰到个病例,要我们去看一看
Chase caught a case in the E.R.He wants us to take a look.
除非是chase玩马球摔断脖子
Unless chase broke his neck falling off his polo pony,
否则他绝不应出现在急救室
he had no reason to be in the E.R.
Cuddy 让他做两周新生儿重症室的轮班
Cuddy put him on a two-week nicu rotation.
病人莫名地抽搐
Patient had an unexplained seizure.
抽搐看着带劲, 医起来无聊,foreman 怎么样了?
Seizures are cool to watch,boring to diagnose.How about foreman?
他该挪着装病的屁股来了
He needs to get his malingering butt back here.
他差点死了
He almost died.
幸好是 "差点"
Almost being the operative word.
嘿
Hey.
怎么样? 看上去很好
How are you doing?You look great.
谢谢. 感觉不错
Thanks.I feel great.
很高兴你回来了
Glad you're back.
Cameron 冲咖啡很差劲,我偏好黑咖啡
Cameron makes lousy coffee.I take mine black,
如同我偏爱脑子受损的神经学家
the way I take my brain-damaged neurologists.
乐于帮忙
Happy to help.
恢复得怎么样?
How you coming along?
说一切都好
Tell her everything's great.
你我都不想看到她自责
Neither of us wants to deal with her guilt.
- 我没有自责,- 当然没有
I don't feel guilty.--Of course not.
该死, 要是每次不小心把人变成白痴,都要感到自责的话
Hell,if people felt guilt every time they accidentally lobotomized a guy...
我想救他的命
I was trying to save his life.
是啊, 动机是好的
Yeah. Your heart was in the right place.
可结果他的脑子被倒腾了
It's just his brain is not quite where it's supposed to be.
告诉她, 一切安好
Tell her everything's great.
真的
It's true.
再没有左右侧颠倒
No more left-side,right-side reversals.
还有短暂失忆和空间感失调
Still some short-term memory loss and spatial processing problems,
不急于求成
but trying not to be too hard on myself.
是. 会拉伤肌肉的
Yeah.Might pull a muscle.
有案例?
We have a case?
抽搐, 非癫痫
Seizure that can't be explained by epilepsy.
- 伴随血钙升高,- 很闷呐
And accompanied by elevated calcium levels.--Still bored.
告诉她为什么
Tell her why.
因为伴随轻微血钙升高的抽搐
Because seizure with mildly elevated calcium is...
很容易诊断
diagnostically simple.
要么是甲亢, 癌症, 钙媒介神经中毒
It's either hyperparathyroid,cancer,or calcium-mediated neurotoxicity.
不错
Well done.
在你想起怎么冲咖啡之前,不准医病人
But until you can remember how to make coffee,hands off the patients.
House.
House
这些让你觉得无聊的病因,急救室都排除了
All those reasons this case bores you...the er has already ruled them out.
肺没事, 做个脑电图, 确认大脑活动正常
Lungs are clear.Get an eeg confirming brain function's okay.
能不能关注下手头的案子?
can we focus on the task at hand?
妈妈为什么抽搐如此剧烈?,把宝宝扔进了洗澡水
Why did mommy twitch so hard that she tossed the baby in with the bathwater?
你不需要我
You don't need me for this.
我当然需要你. 我们是一个团队
Of course I need you.We're a team.
结节性多动脉炎
Polyarteritis nodosa.
肾脏动脉炎症导致血钙升高
Inflamed arteries in the kidneys cause calcium buildup.
脑部动脉炎症导致抽搐
Inflamed arteries in the brain cause seizures.
你是个笨蛋
You're a moron.
看没看文件? 肾脏功能良好
Did you even look at the file?Kidney function's fine.
Whipple氏病,(小肠疾病, 导致消化不良, 体重减轻)
Whipple'S.
什么?
What?
Wipple氏病
Whipple'S.
测试下
Test her.
Cameron 认为是 "W" 打头的,我认为是 "v" 打头的
Cameron thinks it starts with a "W."I'm thinking "V."
爸爸早上呕吐了,也许都得感染了链球菌
Dad vomited this morning. Maybe they've both got strep.
做个咽拭子链球菌培养,你不会把棉签伸到他肛门吧
Think you can do a strep throat culture without the swab ending up in the guy's poop chute?
"V" 代表血管收缩
"V" for vasoconstriction.
就是我的猜测
That's be my guess.
过多的钙导致大脑的血管紧缩
Excess calcium makes blood vessels in the brain clamp down.
最好的情况: 抽搐,最差的情况: 中风
Best-case scenario: Seizure.Worst-case: Stroke.
做数字血管造影
Do a digital extraction angiogram.
Foreman 还没有恢复,Cameron 是个小姑娘
Foreman can't tell up from down.Cameron's a girl.
- 只是机械活,- 对不起, cuddy让我待在这儿
All that mechanical stuff. --Sorry,cuddy says i'm stuck here.
你晚了
You're late.
你在我上锁的办公室里, 再一次
And you are in my locked office.Again.
你藏了什么?
Whatcha got there?
为和 wilson 约会, 准备了别致的小裤裤?
Special panties for your date with wilson?
不是约会, 不关你的事
It's not a date,and it's none of your business.
如果不是约会, 就是公事
If it's not a date,it is business.
如果是公事, 你就不会说, 不关我的事
And if it was business,you wouldn't say it was none of my business.
你要干什么?
What do you want?
我想讨论一下你和 wilson 的约会
I wanna talk about your date with wilson.
- 不是约会,- 真有趣
It's not a date.--This is fun.
把 chase 撤出新生儿重症室,我就闭口不谈你的约会
Spring chase from nicu,and I'll shut up about your date.
新生儿重症室缺人手
Nicu is short-staffed.
你突然不会说谎了
You suddenly lost the ability to lie.
两年里, 没有人从新生儿重症室退出过
Nobody's quit nicu in two years.
如果你在编造理由, 说明本没有理由
And if you're making up reasons,that means there is no reason.
也就是说是他自己要求的, 是不是?
Which means he asked for the assignment,didn't he?
如果chase想避开你, 他有理由这么做
If chase needs a break from you,he should take it.
当然
Absolutely.
爸爸和妈妈都未感染链球菌
Both mom and dad are negative for strep.
你很快就能再操作这些大玩具了
You'll be back playing with the big toys soon.
也许不能. 无论如何, 都好
Or not.Either way,I'm fine.
你无需这么说
You don't have to say that.
没事. 我还可以在研究所工作, 或是教书
It's okay.I can always work in a research lab or teach.
你可以接受?
And you'd be okay with that?
为什么不能?
Why wouldn't I be?
你曾计划寻找赞助, 成立自己的部门
You were planning on pursuing grants of your own.Running a department.
我活着
I'm alive.
换工作, 不会冲咖啡了
Changing jobs,not making coffee--
如果这些事让我苦恼,我就对不起再生的机会
if that stuff bothers me now,I don't deserve the second chance.
据说, 身体的接触有助于痊愈
They say that physical contact helps the healing process.
怎么啦?
What's happening?
你儿子得不到足够的氧气,带 Mason 先生出去
Your son's not getting enough oxygen.Take mr. Mason outside.
肺部收缩了, 得不到空气, 给我4号导管
Lung's collapsed.He's not getting any air.I need an iv catheter!
抽搐?
You have a seizure?
她胸部的肌肉收缩, 不是抽搐
Her chest muscles are contracting.It's something else.
整个背部痉挛,  2毫克劳拉西泮,(治疗癫痫药物)
Her whole back is spasming.I need two milligrams lorazepam,stat.
他没事了
He's okay.
没事的话, 肺就不会收缩
His lung wouldn't collapse if he was okay.
发生了什么?
What the hell is happening?
不知道
I have no idea.
唔... 什么能导致抽搐和血钙上升
so...what causes seizures,hypercalcemia,
还让妈妈弯曲得像gumby小子?,(橡皮泥动画人物)
and the thing where mommy bends like gumby?
正在忙
Little busy here.
啊-哦... 宝宝的肺随时都会失灵
Uh-oh...baby's lungs are gonna conk out any minute.
可能是想应付这点
Probably wanna deal with that.
我让老板满足之后, 就着手干这个
I'll get right on it as soon as I finish indulging my boss.
一心二用
Multitask.
化学性肺炎
Chemical pneumonitis.
在宝宝溺水的时候, 浴泡跑进了肺里
Bubble bath got into the baby's lungs when he was underwater.
给他用强的松,保持吸入高浓度氧
Start him on prednisone.Keep him on high fi-02.
开始让我满足吧
Let the indulging commence.
锂盐中毒可以导致妈妈的三个症状
Lithium could cause all three of the mother's symptoms.
没有记录她使用锂盐,(存于精神类药物中)
No record she's on lithium.
毒性测试也是阴性的
And tox screen was negative.
锂不能被基本毒性检测发现, 稻草人
Lithium doesn't show on a basic tox screen,scarecrow.
骨髓瘤细胞侵犯脑膜也适用所有症状
Myelomatous meningitis could also cover everything.
罕见血癌的罕见并发症
Rare complications of a rare blood cancer.
你并非不可救药
You're not totally hopeless.
做血清蛋白电泳,和核磁共振来检查骨髓瘤
Get an s-pep and an mri for myelomatous meningitis.
搜查病人家里有没有锂
Search the patient's place for lithium.
宝宝肺部问题是细菌性的,不是化学性的, 做Ecmo
Baby's lung problem is bacterial,not chemical--start ecmo.
寻找锂的同时
While you're searching for the lithium,
取水的样本, 查一下水管
take a water sample and check the pipes.
还要我写下来吗?
You want me to write this down for you?
问你呀, 他差点死了之后,怎么就不好玩了?
I ask you,is almost dying any excuse for not being fun?
我不会给宝宝做Ecmo
I'm not putting that baby on ecmo.
洗澡水里有细菌的概率实在是--
The chance of there being bacteria in bathwater--
你为什么不愿为我工作?
why don't you wanna work for me?
我友善, 在聚会上也逗趣
I'm nice,and fun at parties.
我干新生儿监护, 不是因为你
I'm not working nicu because of you.
x光显示宝宝是化学性肺炎
The baby's x-ray suggested chemical pneumonitis.
我看着不是, x光太笼统了
Not to me.X-ray was too consolidated.
你为什么到这里来?
So why are you down here?
想把你约会的对象扩展到,早产儿至九岁儿童?
Hoping to expand your make-out pool to include the preemie to nine-year-old demographic?
我需要离开
I needed a break.
离开这些病人
From the patients.
他们总对我们说谎
They lie to us all the time.
Foreman 为了救个嗑药的警察,差点死了
Foreman almost died trying to save a drug-dealing cop.
我想避开一会儿
I just wanted to get away from that for a while.
一通胡言
What a complete load of crap.
你以为我是谁?,听你诉苦, 就被钓上的护士?
What am I,a nurse you're trying to prep with this vulnerability thing?
Ecmo会让他死
Ecmo could kill him.
不着手做Ecmo, 感染就会爆发
You don't start him on ecmo,and that infection could rampage
在他体内狂欢, 如同夺冠后的活塞队球迷
through his body like pistons fans after a championship.
你看着办
But you do it your way.
死婴最诚实
Nothing more honest than a dead baby.
Ecmo代表体外膜性氧合术
Ecmo stands for extra corporeal membrane oxygenation.
意思是移除你儿子的血液--
Basicall we remove your son's blood--
所有的血?
all of his blood?
血液流经机器, 拿掉二氧化碳, 注入氧气
We run it through a machine,which takes out carbon dioxide and adds oxygen.
再温热血液, 重新注入体内
Then we re-warm the blood and run it back into his body.
内出血的风险很大, 他还要忍受--
There is a significant risk of internal hemorrhaging,and he may also suffer--
你已经给他用抗生素了,不能对抗感染吗?
you put him on antibiotics.Won't that take care of the infection?
还不够快
Not fast enough.
你确定这对 mikey 最有利吗?
Are you sure this is mikey's best shot?
当然
Absolutely.
- Cuddy 的垃圾,- 不是她的咯
Cuddy's trash.--Not anymore.
花了大价钱了
Paid good money for it.
看看她买了什么
Look at what she bought.
红苜蓿
Red clover.
红苜蓿能用来干什么, Wilson 医生?
What is red clover used for,dr. Wilson?
也可以用来治疗哮喘
It's also used to treat asthma.
牛皮藓...关节疼痛
Psoriasis...joint pain.
她没有喘, 皮肤掉屑, 疼痛
She doesn't wheeze,flake,or ache.
所以她没有邀请呼吸科,或皮肤病医师吃晚餐
And she didn't ask a pulmonologist or a dermatologist for dinner.
她请了肿瘤学家
She invited an oncologist.
不是约会, 是医学参考
It's not a date.It's a consult.
妈妈的 mri 显示没有结块, 脓肿,没有迹象--
Mom's mri was negative for masses,abscesses.There's no sign she has--
太好了. 等查出什么来, 再--
fascinating.Call me when we have--
她蛛网膜下出血
she has a subarachnoid bleed.
病人为什么颅内出血?
So why is our patient bleeding into her brain?
血液检查发现凝血酶原时间变长
Her blood workup shows her pro-time's elevated.
出血是因为血不凝了,为什么不凝血?
She's bleeding because she's not clotting.So why is she not clotting?
带回来什么, 爸爸?
What'd you bring us,daddy?
唯一影响状态的药物是伏特加
Only mood-altering drug was vodka.
藏在橱背后
The back of a drawer.
藏匿欢饮, 百分百是酒鬼的行径,这能解释出血
Hiding booze is classic alcoholic behavior.That'd explain the bleeding.
什么出血?
What bleeding?
你不记得了?
You don't remember?
她早上喷你一身的血. 开玩笑
She bled all over you this morning.Kidding.
白痴真好玩. 难怪每个村子都有一个傻子
Idiots are fun.No wonder every village wants one.
如果她酗酒,罹患血钙过高的可能性更大
If she's an alcoholic,she would also be more prone to hypercalcemia.
但毒性检测未发现酒精
But the tox screen was negative for alcohol.
嘿, 这本是你的猜测
Hey,it was your idea.
现在更好了
Now it's even better.
妈妈戒酒了, 得了dts, 解释了昏厥,(dts 酒精戒断综合症, 震颤, 妄想)
Mommy quits,she gets the dts.Even explains the seizure.
也可能是角色转换症
Also fits conversion disorder.
他们负债累累, 丈夫整日价工作,新生了宝宝
They're deep in debt.He's working round the clock.They got a new baby.
抽搐可能是心理紧张激发
I think the seizure was a physical response to psychological stress.
酗酒的妈妈, 解释了更多的症状
Boozy mommy covers more symptoms.
在dts致死前, 给她镇静剂, 让她昏眠
Put her in a nice phenobarbital coma before the dts kill her.
你去干什么?
Where are you going?
让她镇静昏睡
To put her in a pheno coma.
万一我错了呢? 也许爸爸才是酒鬼?
What if I'm wrong?What if daddy's the drunk?
你到底要不要给她用镇静剂？
You want us to give her the pheno or not?
我要他争辩
I want him to argue his point.
我以为你考虑过父亲, 排除他了
I assumed you considered the father and ruled him out.
怎么说来着的?,"你一假定, 就成眼中钉."
What's that saying?"When you ass-sume,you become a pain in the ass to me."
我为什么要争论? 你制服了我
Why should I argue?You'd just overrule me.
- 够了! 养养马, 种种西瓜去吧.,- house!
Enough! Get a pony or a watermelon farm.--House!
他怎么没有反应. 我要他有点人样
I need him to react.I need him to act like a human being.
我要他快点恢复讨人嫌的死后重生
I need him to get over this boring near-death rebirth.
我改变了. 这无法恢复
I have changed.It's not something you get over.
濒死经历或许会改变一切
Nearly dying changes everything forever.
在两个月以内. 两个月已经过长了
For about two months.Two months is too long.
我要我聘请的那个人回来, 现在
I need the guy i hired back,now.
无论你的痛苦多么想要同伴,我的痛苦不与你做伴
Now matter how much your misery loves company,it's not getting mine.
我去和爸爸谈谈. Cameron去找妈妈
I'll talk to the dad.Cameron can take the mom.
会查出妈妈是不是酒鬼
We'll figure out if mom was a drinkerer.
浪费时间. 在dts杀死她之前, 让她昏迷
Waste of time.Put her in a coma before the dts kill her.
唔...
So...
是分居还是...
is this a separation or...
嗯, 律师找好了. 朋友们分了阵营
well,lawyers have been hired.Friends divvied up.
奇怪的是, 她没有争房子
Oddly,she didn't fight me for house.
至少你们没孩子
At least there aren'T...kids involved.
只要搞定彼此二人
You just have each other to deal with.
如果有孩子的话,也许我们会付出更多
If there had been kids,maybe we would have done more of that.
你想要孩子?
Do you want kids?
看, 有没有特别的事情你想--
Listen,is there anything in particular you wanted to--
- 有关医院的?,- 只是交流感情
hospital business or--catching up.
我是说, 你看
I mean,you know,it's not like...
我们两人家里都没人等着赶回去
either one of us has anybody to run home to.
没有
No.
感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
还行, 有点头昏眼花
Okay.A little groggy.
有人来看你
There's somebody here to see you.
嘿, mikey. 妈妈醒了
Hey,mikey.Mommy's awake.
哦, mikey. 哦, 天, 我吓坏了
Oh,mikey.Oh,gosh,I was so scared.
哦, 我爱你. 我真爱你
Oh,I love you.I love you so much.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不需要道歉
You don't have anything to be sorry about.
你病了
You were sick.
原来她和丈夫在嗜酒劝戒会相识
Turns out she and her husband met in aa.
显然, 她复发了
Obviously,she slipped.
猜得好
Good call.
并不困难, 因另一个方案,是你愚蠢的心理紊乱理论
It wasn't hard,considering my other choice was your stupid psych theory.
那其实并不愚蠢
Which was not stupid.
警告你, 必要时, 我会扔核炸弹
I tell you,I'm gonna drop the n-bomb if I have to.
你对冲突上瘾了
You're addicted to conflict.
改名字了? (house原对止痛药上瘾)
Did they change the name?
不拖上 chase, 你也能处理这案例
You could have handled this patient without dragging chase in.
但是他不愿加入, 让你狠得牙痒痒
But that fact that he didn't want in killed you.
就好比你不能激怒我一样
Just like the fact you can't get a rise out of me.
宝宝在哪里?
Where's the baby?
放开我!
Get off me!
不! 我必须这么做!
No! I have to do this!
没有呼吸声. 急救车, 肾上腺素
No breath sounds.Crash cart and epi,stat!
说了, 你的心理紊乱理论不愚蠢
Told you your psych theory wasn't stupid.
你儿子没事
Your son is stable.
但缺氧毁了他的肾脏
But the lack of oxygen damaged his kidneys.
她肯定是翻身, 不小心压到了
She must have rolled over on him by mistake.
Mason 先生... 我亲眼所见
Mr. Mason...I was there.
你妻子要闷死你儿子
Your wife tried to smother your son.
不可能
That's impossible.
Kara 不会伤害 mikey
Kara would never hurt mikey.
他知道, 他们说 mikey 知道
He knows.They said mikey knows.
你听到声音?
You hear voices?
他们不停地说, 那样对mikey最好...
They wouldn't quit saying that mikey would be better off if...
他们是对的
they were right.
试着治疗的抽搐, 本不存在
We've been trying to diagnose a seizure that didn't exist.
她被丈夫发现时, 就假装
She faked it when her husband caught her.
不是她装出来的
I don't think she faked it.
她在溺死孩子时, 正好抽疯了?
She just happened to seize right in the middle of drowning her child?
孩子倒是逃过一劫
Good break for the kid.
嘿, 对 foreman 客气点
Hey,take it easy on foreman.
他可是在脑叶被秘密打结的情况下干活
He's playing with one lobe tied behind his back.
产后忧郁症让她想溺死自己的孩子
Postpartum psychosis makes her want to drown her kid.
内心的交战促发了抽搐
The internal conflict triggers a seizure.
你知道还有什么是诱因?
You know what else might be a trigger?
身体上的疾病. 很荒谬吧, 我知道
Physical illness. It's a wild idea,I know.
特别是当她没什么明显的生理症状
Especially since she doesn't have any obviously physical symptoms.
"没有"内出血和血钙超量
Like internal bleeding or excess calcium.
我去抽点血. 检查一下
I'll draw some blood.test for it.
天, 你又来了! 你就不能跟我吵吗?!
Jeez,you've done it again!Will you argue with me?!
酒鬼常饮食不善. 可以解释出血和血钙
Drinkers don't eat right.Explains the bleeding and the calcium.
可能只是饮酒过度
This might just be some crazy drunk,
我却告诉你, 她会由于脑膜骨髓瘤而死
and I'm telling you that she's about to die of myelomatous meningitis.
- 我们已经查过了,- 没错, 疯狂的想法
We already tested for--exactly!It's an insane idea.
好, 你要我干什么?
Okay.What do you want me to do?
有点原创想法
Have an original thought.
现在, 诱使她再次发病
In the meantime,stress her into having another seizure.
不行, 她在使用氟哌啶醇 (强镇定剂)
We can't,she's on haloperidol.
不可以, 还因为太危险, 且不人道
You also can't because it's dangerous and highly unethical.
不过, 被抓住时, 你可以假装不会冲咖啡
Therefore,if you get caught,pretend you can't make coffee.
智力缺陷让人放松警惕
Mental defectives get tons of slack.
停用氟哌啶醇.,把她连上脑电图扫描, 闪光刺激她
Take off the haloperidol. Hook her up to an eeg,flash some lights.
让她喘气, 注射安慰剂,(没有药理作用的药剂)
Make her pant.Shoot her up with a placebo.
如果她开始抽搐,脑电图也跟着抽, 那是真的
When she starts twitching,if the machine twitches along,it's real...if not,
如果没有, 叫警察来, 她是个精神病杀手
call the cops,'cause she's a psycho killer.
- 别逼他了,- 别保护他了
Stop pushing him.--stop protecting him.
他需要保护
He needs it.
不需要, 如果他想好起来
Not if he wants to get better.
他可能好不了了
He might not be able to get better.
嗯, 这样的话, 我就重新请个神经学家
Well,then,I need a new neurologist.
他因为工作而病
He got sick doing his job.
如果他因公殉职, 就不用付他薪水了
If he got killed doing his job,I wouldn't keep him on the payroll.
我不管你有多内疚,还是为他的重生有多感动
I don't care how guilty you feel or how touched you are by his reborn spirit.
我没有被感动
I'm not touched.
那你是由内疚驱使
Then you're guilt-ridden.
我没有内疚
I'm not guilt-ridden.
那你真是可悲
Then you're pathetic.
现在, 我被激怒了!,让他在癫痫实验室里彻夜工作
Right now,I'm annoyed!Keeping him up all night in a seizure lab
不利于他的康复! 太辛苦了!
is not the way to advance his recovery!It's too much!
不错. 你应该盯着点
You're right.You should stick around.
以防他出错
Make sure he doesn't screw up.
kara, 盯着灯光看
kara,look directly into the light.
盯着看
Keep looking.
以为你今天下班了
Thought you'd be gone for the day.
想等到骨髓切片检查结果出来
Thought I'd wait for the bone marrow biopsy results.
House 派你来照看我, 是吗?
House sent you to baby-sit me,didn't he?
他让我等着结果
He asked me to wait for the results.
哦, cameron, 没事的
Oh,cameron,it's fine.
当然了
Of course it is.
瞧, 几星期前,你因为我不把你当朋友而难过
look,A few weeks ago,you were upset that I didn't consider you a friend.
现在, 你却因为我快乐而难过
Now you're upset that I'm happy?
无话可说, 很明显, 我是个贱人
What can I say?Apparently,I'm a bitch.
我可没说哦
I didn't say that.
让人生气
It's annoying.
坚持你的每一天是上天恩赐如同
Insisting every day of your life is a blessing is
指正别人都是肤浅的. 太老套了
basically calling everyone else shallow.It gets old.
- 抱歉
--Sorry.
- 哦, 省省吧
--Oh,give it a rest.
晚餐怎么样?
How was dinner?
Cuddy 没有提到肿瘤
Cuddy did not mention cancer.
她临阵退缩了
She lost her nerve.
那是个约会
It was a date.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
PCR实验,(多聚酶链式反应, 扩增DNA)
Pcr test.
你亲自做? 在大半夜的
You're doing it yourself?In the middle of the night.
从勺子上
On a spoon.
Cuddy的勺子
Cuddy's spoon.
检查她的口水, 是否有癌症标记
I'm checking her saliva for cancer markers.
是啊... 我也常在约会后这么做
Yeah...I do that after all my dates too.
你是公认的好人
People think you're the nice one.
为什么对 cuddy 这么关心?
Why are you so worried about cuddy?
你先说
You go first.
你渴望这是个约会
You desperately want this to be a date.
不是约会那就是癌症了
Because the alternative is cancer.
承认你喜欢她吧
Just admit that you like her.
她聪明, 有趣
She's smart,funny.
身材玲珑
Got a zesty bod.
真好, 你不在乎她是个魔鬼
It's great you can look beyond the fact she's the devil.
我偷了她的勺子, 你偷了她的垃圾
I stole a spoon.You stole her garbage.
她是我的老板
She's my boss.
她要是病了, 医院就会把她换下
She gets sick,the hospital might replace her.
特别当她病死时
Especially if she dies.
我就得学习怎么操控新老板
I'd have to learn how to manipulate someone new.
我想我会哭的
I think I'm gonna cry.
有结果时告诉我
Find me when the results come in.
Mason 先生, 由于你孩子肾脏的损坏
Mr. Mason...because of the damage done to your son's kidneys,
他血钾的含量直升
his potassium is climbing.
会导致不规律的心跳
It's causing irregular heartbeats.
我加倍了药量, 开始给他做透析
I'm doubling the meds and starting him on dialysis.
除非他血钾降下来...
Unless we get his potassium down...
不然, 他心脏病发作
he's gonna have a heart attack.
Kara, 再要几分钟就好
Kara,just another few minutes.
活检结果出来了, 没有得脑膜骨髓瘤
Biopsy's back.She's negative for myelomatous meningitis.
她也没有发作
And she's not seizing.
那么我们和 house 都错了
So we're wrong and house is wrong.
你可以接受?
And you're okay with that?
她有反应了
She's seizing.
她没有动作
She's not doing anything.
大脑活动没有加快. 而是变缓慢了
Brain activity isn't aclerating.It's slowing down.
肌肉僵硬, 不自觉握放和吮吸动作
muscle rigidity,involuntary grasping and sucking motions.
她得了脑部谵妄
She's in an encephalopathic delirium.
嗯, 原发性的生理疾病. 排除了几件事
Mmm,a genuine physiological illness.That rules out a few things.
诸如, 我想想?
Like what,I wonder?
产后忧郁症和角色转换失调
Postpartum psychosis and conversion disorder.
当个好失败者的要点...你仍旧是失败者
Thing about being a good loser...you're still a loser.
谵妄说明她的大脑停止运转
The delirium means her brain is shutting down,
切换到最本能功用
reverting to its most instinctual functions.
因病情发展了, 也许可以看作是进展
Since it's progressing,maybe we can assume it's progressive.
说明距离大脑关门歇业就不远了
Which means it won't be long before the brain closes shop altogether.
有主意吗?
Ideas?
他心室纤维颤动
He's in v fib!
血钾还是太高了
Potassium's still too high.
没有脉搏, 把机器拿开
No pulse.Get him off the machine.
调到10. 离手
Charge at 10.Clear.
还在室颤
Still in v fib.
再打一针肾上腺素
Another amp of epi.
该死,chase不该在新生儿重症室浪费时间
Damn it,chase shouldn't be wasting his time in nicu.
可能是 wernicke 脑病,(急性威胁生命的神经系统综合征)
Could be wernicke'S.
不, 硫胺 (维生素B1) 能治疗wernicke病,在用镇静剂时给药了
No,treatment for wernicke's is thiamine.We gave her that together with the pheno.
谵妄可能由锂引发,我知道没有发现, 但是--
Delirium points to lithium.I know we didn't find any,but--
她入院后加重, 除非她还偷运了些进来
she's have to be smuggling it in to be getting sicker.
Whipple氏病也能引起脑部谵妄
Whipple's causes encephalopathic delirium.
检测呈阴性
Test was negative.
检测可能出错
The test could have been wrong.
点子可不是汽水罐
Ideas are not soda cans.
没有再利用这一说
Recycling sucks.
要的是崭新, 闪亮的
We need something new and shiny.
要不旧衣新穿,挑个老点子, 擦擦亮, 加入新的症状
Or go retro.Take an old idea,shine it up,add a new symptom.
脑部谵妄
Encephalopathic delirium.
Pellagra,(糙皮病, 烟酸缺乏)
Pellagra.
她酗酒. 酒鬼容易得糙皮病
She drinks.Alcoholics get pellagra.
他们吃垃圾食物, 不摄入烟酸
They eat lousy diets,so no niacin.
他同意我观点. 太震惊了
He agrees with me.What a shock.
嗯, 你是对的
Well,you're right.
烟酸缺乏, 使大脑饥饿
Lack of niacin starves the brain.
神经元关闭, 导致惊厥, 谵妄和精神失常
Neurons shut down,causes seizures,encephalopathic delirium,and psychosis.
给她用烟酸, 就能从谵妄中恢复理智
We give kara niacin,she'll come out of her delirium and she'll be totally sane.
她永不能恢复理智
Don't think she's ever gonna be sane again.
她孩子刚刚死了
Her son just died.
感觉如何?
How do you feel?
我的, 唔...胃有点痛
my,uh...stomach kind of hurts.
我要问你点问题, 看你好了没有
I need to ask you some questions.See how you're doing.
告诉我你的名字
Tell me your name.
Kara mason. 我儿子在这里吗?
Kara mason.Is my son here?
出生年月?
When were you born?
请告诉我... michael在哪里? 他好吗?
Please...where's michael?Is he okay?
你听到除我之外的声音吗?
Do you hear any other voices besides mine?
没有! 回答我
No! Answer me.
你曾产生幻觉
You've been suffering from delusions.
因维生素缺乏导致: 烟酸缺乏
They were caused by a vitamin deficiency: Pellagra.
让你相信不存在的事
It made you believe things that were not real.
比如声音
Like the voices.
我, 嗯... 记得对 mikey 做过什么
I,uh...remember doing things to mikey.
那是真实的吗?
Were those real?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
那我...
So I...
你要闷死孩子
you tried to suffocate your son.
但, 你... 你制止我了
But I...you...you stopped me.
还有... 另一个医生让 mikey 又呼吸了
And,uh...that other doctor.He got mikey breathing.
你孩子的器官受损太严重了
Your son's organs were damaged too severely.
他今天早上死了
He passed away this morning.
噢, 不. 不, 不, 不, 不! 不!
Oh,no.No,no,no,no,no!No!
噢, 天呐! 不!
Oh,my god! No!
噢, 我的天
Oh,my god.
烟酸缺乏不会导致呕血
pellagra doesn't cause bloody vomit.
她还病着, 而且在恶化
She's still sick,and getting worse.
什么导致烟酸缺乏和狂喷血?
So what causes pellagra and crimson spew?
宝宝死了, 虽然悲伤, 但不是我们的难题
Dead baby,while sad,not our problem.
我应给他更多的降钾树脂
I should have given him more polystyrene.
你杀了他
You killed him.
你要是不振作, 还会杀了他妈妈
If you don't get over it,you're gonna kill mama too.
酗酒造成她缺烟酸,也许也能解释呕吐. 胃炎
her alcoholism caused the pellagra.Maybe it also explains the vomiting.Gastritis.
胃炎的药没起作用
Gastritis meds aren't helping.
能够证实她的叙述, 她戒了酒精
Which may confirm her story she only slipped once.
把饮酒从方程式移走,内出血, 高血钙, 惊厥
You remove the drinking from the equation,internal bleeding,hypercalcemia,seizure,
烟酸缺乏, 都要新的解释
and pellagra are all back in.
Chase, 把你的头从死婴的屁股里拔出来,关注一下垂死的--
Chase will you get your head out of the dead ba's butt and focus on the barely alive--
你给了小孩多少降钾树脂
how much polystyrene did you give the kid?
一克
One gram.
血钾还是不停升高
His potassium just kept rising.
我要你的孩子
I need your son.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你妻子的医生, 你孩子和她可能情况相同
Your wife's doctor.Your son may have had the same condition she does.
我孩子没有得病. 是她害死的
My son didn't have a condition.She killed him.
如果检查她的肠子, 她血会喷涌
If I biopsy her intestine,she'll bleed out.
很明显他不会了
He obviously won'T.
不准你用我儿子的身体来帮助她
You're not using my son's body to help her.
好, 用一瓶啤酒交换行吗?
Okay. How about trading him for a beer?
或许你更偏爱威士忌
Or maybe you're more of a whisky guy.
进医院的那天早晨,你不是感染了链球菌, 或是恶心
You didn't have strep or a stomach bug the morning you came in.
呕吐是因为宿醉
You puked because you were hung over.
指控一个康复了的酒鬼故态复萌,多数情况下, 你是正确的
Accuse a recovered drunk of slipping,most of the time,you'd be right.
我喝酒了
So I drink.
仿佛这是我的过错
You're acting like this is my fault.
人们会为你感到难过
People are gonna feel sorry for you.
他们安慰你, 你无法预知,事实上, 你可以
They'll tell you that you can't anticipate the unthinkable.The fact is,you can.
只是没那么愉快
It's just not all that pleasant.
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything about--
我知道人在疯狂到杀害某人前
I know that people don't get crazy enough to kill someone
会首先被发现行止疯狂
without first being crazy enough for someone to notice.
有多少次, 你出去饮酒, 因为她哭泣?
How many times did you go out for a drink because she was crying?
多少次你留下工作
How many times did you stay at work
因为你不想听到, 她说,她是多么糟糕的母亲
because you couldn't listen to her telling you what a bad mother she is?
当她安静时, 你宽心了
You were relieved when she shut down.
她数小时静坐
Just sat staring for hours at a time.
把枕头蒙在孩子头上
She held the pillow over his head.
她发疯时, 你熟睡
You slept while she went nuts.
- 可能没那么精确, 但--
--Not exactly a draw,but--
-- 你有病吗?
--what is wrong with you?
什么样的人, 会在此时说出这种话
What kind of a person says those things now.
让我做检测
Let me do the test.
能够多少减轻你的负罪感
It'll be one less thing for you to feel crappy about.
弄到个死宝宝, 给你做组织检查
Got a dead baby for you to biopsy.
让 cameron 去做
Let cameron do it.
你不是喜爱重症婴儿监护吗?
You love working nicu?
我能把你调过去
I could get you transferred.
告诉过你了, 我就是想信任病人
I told you,I just wanted to trust patients.
别针对病人胡扯了
You don't give a crap about patients.
你的薪水支票
Your paycheck.
你挣双份了
You've been double-dipping.
在新生儿室领钱, 这里是带薪假期
Taking your vacation time here while drawing a salary in nicu.
奇怪. 富哥儿做这么多, 为了额外的钱
Strange.Rich boy doing all that for some extra cash.
我不富有
I'm not rich.
你爸爸有钱. 现在他死了
But your dad was.Now he's dead.
如果你没钱了, 说明老爸没给你
If you're not rich,that means that daddy cut you out.
我没钱
I'm not rich.
别让它改变你
Don't let it change you.
还有, 做检查
And do the test.
应承的主, 拥 micha 入怀
God of confession,take micha into your arms.
迎他进入天国, 那里没有悲哀
Welcome him into paradise where there'll be no sorrow,
没有哭泣, 没有伤痛. 安乐至恒
no weeping,and no pain.Peace and joy forevermore.
对不起
I'm sorry.
是个约会, cuddy对所有癌症标记都呈阴性
It was a date.Cuddy's negative for all cancer markers.
是个约会
It was a date.
宝宝的肠绒毛轻微萎缩
Baby's intestines show slight villous atrophy.
宝宝的肠绒毛怎么会压平？
Why would a baby have flattened villi?
因为他用了降钾树脂
He was being treated with polystyrene.
- 降钾树脂不会,- 本来是不会
Polystyrene shouldn't--it didn'T.
问题是, 新生儿监护室使用了什么?,和它结合了
Question is,what did they use in the nicu to bind it together?
- 小麦谷蛋白,- 那是有益的
Wheat gluten.--That's great stuff.
除非你的身体承受不了
Unless your body can't tolerate it.
宝宝不是早期哭闹症，他得了乳糜泻？,(吸收不良症候群)
The baby didn't have colic,he had celiac disease?
和妈妈一样
Just like mom.
乳糜泻会因许多压力而诱发
Celiac can be triggered by all kinds of stress.
账单, 分娩, 酒鬼丈夫
Bills,childbirth,drunk husband.
每次她吃了一碗意粉, 一片面包, 酱油
Every time she had a bowl of pasta or a slice of bread or a slosh of soy sauce,
她的小肠就损坏一些
her small intestine became more damaged.
愈发不能吸收维生素和矿物质入血液
Less able to absorb the vitamins and minerals into her bloodstream.
身体得不到足够烟酸. 导致了糙皮症
Her body couldn't absorb enough niacin.Caused the pellagra.
不能吸收维生素K, 导致出血
Couldn't absorb vitamin K.Caused the bleeding.
乳糜泻也让宝宝的药物不起作用
And celiac is why the baby's meds didn't work.
他的身体吸收不到药物
His body just couldn't absorb them.
给妈妈输营养液, 不含谷蛋白
Switch mom to iv nutrition.It's gluten-free.
会重整她的小肠绒毛
It'll spruce her villi right up.
不, 乳糜泻导致营养缺乏,可病人血钙盈余
No,celiac causes nutritional deprivation.Our patient has excess calcium.
告诉他们什么导致血钙盈余
Tell them what causes excess calcium.
反复的恶性呕吐
With a chaser of bloody vomit.
乳糜泻的病人易得胃内膜癌
Celiac patients are susceptible to cancer of the stomach lining.
她有胃粘膜淋巴瘤
She has malt lymphoma.
她现在是你的病人了
She's your patient now.
不是一次约会
And it wasn't a date.
你没有癌症
You don't have cancer.
你也没有侏儒症
You don't have dwarfism.
你无法证明哦
You have no proof of that.
可是我有这个
I,on the other hand,have this.
没有得到同意, 就对我做了一次 pcr？
You ran a pcr on me without my consent?
嘿, 好消息
Hey,it's good news.
真的?真难理解,由于对隐私的粗暴侵犯
Really?It's just hard to access because of this overwhelming sense of personal violation.
用你自己的时间来缓和情绪吧
Deal with it on your own time.
坏消息...
Bad news...
雌激素过高了
estrogen is too high.
无论你对多少人宣扬过
No matter how many people you tell otherwise,
我, 从来都是个女人, 雌激素很正常
I am,and always have been,a woman.Estrogen is normal.
没这么高. 一周后才应该这么高
Not this much.Not for at least another week.
那时是你的排卵期
That's when you ovulate.
什么? 你监控我的生理期?
What?You monitor my periods?
依据是... 当我变得易怒, 还是...
Based on...when I get bitchy or...
每个月一次, 当你离开幼儿癌症病房,你的眼睛闪着泪光
once a month,when you leave the kids' cancer ward,your eyes glisten.
三天之后, 你会破除不吃糖的禁忌
And about three days later,you break your ban on sugar
在餐厅灌下一桶冰酸奶, 覆着巧克力碎屑
and chow down a bucket of frozen yogurt in the cafeteria,sprinkles included.
根据上一次见到酸奶景象
Based on the last yogurt sighting,
你还有一周才排卵
you've got another week before you ovulate.
你在服用受孕药
Your on fertility meds.
红苜蓿是草本催化剂
With red clover as an herbal booster.
和 wilson 的晚餐是演习
And that dinner with wilson was an audition.
真可惜, 他的小船没有靠岸,他本会很开心的
It's too bad he didn't land the gig.He would have had fun.
我考虑精子捐赠, 不是合欢
I was considering a donation.Not a party.
那么... 什么时候... 轮到我们的晚餐?
So...when is our...dinner?
他会多失望啊
he's gonna be so disappointed.
不错. 我娱乐了你们一把
Right.You two are gonna have a lot of fun with this.
你的病人不让我碰她
Your patient won't let me touch her.
我害了自己的孩子
I killed my son.
轮到我说显而易见的事了?
Is it my turn to say something obvious now?
噢, 我知道. 你当时神智不清
Oh,I know.You were insane.
我干的. 我选择这么做
I did it.I chose to do it.
就像糖尿病患者选择不制造胰岛素
Like diabetics choose to not produce insulin.
听着, 有些人病了
Listen,someone got sick.
有些人死了. 每天都发生
Someone died.It happens every day.
这里唯一的差别是...,病和死的不是同一个人
The only difference in this case is...it wasn't the same someone.
我可以制止的
I could have stopped.
我本可以不听那些幻音
I didn't have to listen to those voices.
说得像个真正理智的人
Spoken like a true sane person.
不是你的错. 现在你健康了
This is not your fault.You're healthy now.
除了癌症
Except for the cancer.
那些声音... 在我的感觉...,真实如同michael的小手
Those voices...felt as real to me as...as michael's hand.
当他就在我怀里, 吮奶时
Right here,when he nursed.
还有... 他的发香
And...the smell of his hair.
你不应受死
You do not deserve to die.
也许
Maybe.
我不想活了
I don't wanna live.
她说不
She said no.
我们可以声称她精神不稳定,,指定一个医学代理人
So we get her declared unstable,appoint a medical proxy.
她曾经不稳定. 现在完全理性了
She was unstable.Now she's sane.
她有权利拒绝治疗
She's entitled to refuse the treatment.
你必须改变她的心意. 不能袖手旁观
You have to change her mind.You can't just walk away.
好! 走进去告诉她, 每一天都是恩赐
Fine!Go on in there and tell her that every day is a blessing.
"你杀了自己的孩子. 遗忘吧,想开点, 至少你还活着."
"So you killed your baby.Shake it off.Think positive.At least you're alive."
当你自己都不再信仰时,很难取信于人了, 是吗?
Kind of hard to sell when you don't believe it,huh?
你从没有信仰过
And you never believed it.
你只是想经历的磨难, 能有些意义
You just wanted all that crap you went through to mean something.
告诉你, 没有意义. 从没有过. 欢迎回来
Well,it didn't mean anything.It never does.Welcome back.
这为什么如此对我? 我本来很愉快
Why are you doing this to me?I was happy.
你热切地想要觉得满足
You were aspiring to be content.
不要就语义争辩
Don't give me a semantic argument.
我满意生活的原样! 这就是幸福
I was content with the way things were!That's what happiness is.
是, 如果每个人都为已有的感到满足,多么美妙的世界
Yeah,if we were all just satisfied with what we had,what a beautiful world it would be.
我们都将在污秽中饥饿至死,不过至少我们快乐
We'd all slowly starve to death in our own filth,but at least we'd be happy.
听着, 我要你在这份工作中体现价值
Listen,I need your self-worth to hang on this job.
你所具备的, 让你超凡脱俗
For kicking ass here to be all that lets you rise above miserable.
要是每天清晨醒来就已足够, 我不需要你
If waking up in the morning is enough,I don't need U.
我能承受住
I can live with that.
不, 你不能. 再不能了
No,you can'T.Not anymore.
如果你接受治疗, 也许我们能...
If you got treatment,then maybe we could...
你见到 mikey 时...
when you see mikey...
告诉他, 爸爸对不起他
tell him his dad says he's sorry.
嗨
Hi.
晚安. 晚安
Night.Good night.
你告诉 cuddy, 我们查她有没有得癌症?
Did you tell cuddy we tested her for cancer?
是的
Yeah.
怎么说?
And?
不是约会
It wasn't a date..
原来就是皮肤损伤
Turned out she had some skin lesions.
遗传学办法当然查不到了
Guess there was no genetic predisposition.
你录下拉拉至上了?
You tivo the l word?